A Guide to the Credentials Committee records of the Virginia Board of Medicine, 1980-1985.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Credentials Committee records of the Virginia Board of Medicine,
1980-1985.
The Library of Virginia
35732
Virginia. Dept. of Health Professions.
.7 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Administrative Information
Arranged chronologically.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions
Acquisition Information
Accession 35732 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 02/18/1998.
Historical Information
Regulation of the health professions began late in the nineteenth century. On January 31, 1884, the General Assembly passed an act creating the Board of Medical Examiners to certify physicians for practice in Virginia. In 1973 the name was changed to the Board of Medicine.
The Dept. of Health Regulatory Boards was created by an act passed by the General Assembly on March 31, 1977, to provide administrative services to the health regulatory boards of the state. The boards continue to regulate their professions through the examination, licensing, and disciplining of the practitioners of health science. In 1986, the Dept. of Health Regulatory Boards became the Dept. of Health Professions. Its mission is to enhance the delivery of safe and competent health care by licensing qualified health care professionals, enforcing standards of practice, and providing information to both practitioners and consumers of health care services.
Scope and Content
Meeting records, 1980 July-1985 Nov, document the meetings, activities, discussions, policy decisions, and recommendations of the Credentials Committee of the Board of Medicine. Meeting records contain agendas, correspondence, legislation, minutes, notes, publications, regulations and reports. Many of the records are related to the evaluation of foreign medical schools.
Contents List
- Credentials Committee records of the Virginia Board of Medicine, 1980-1985.
  - Meeting records, 1980 July 19. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Meeting records, 1981 Mar 26. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Meeting records, 1981 June 24. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meeting records, 1981 Nov 11. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Meeting records, 1982 Mar 24. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting records, 1982 Apr 24. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Meeting records, 1982 June 19. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Meeting records, 1982 Aug 18. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Meeting records, 1982 Oct 27. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Meeting records, 1983 Feb 23. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Meeting records, 1983 Apr 22. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meeting records, 1983 June 22. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Meeting records, 1983 Oct 21. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Meeting records, 1983 Nov 17. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Meeting records, 1984 Feb 17. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Meeting records, 1984 Apr 13. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Meeting records, 1984 June 15. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Meeting records, 1984 Aug 31. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meeting records, 1984 Sept 21. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meeting records, 1984 Nov 29. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meeting records, 1985 Feb 15-16. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Meeting records, 1985 Apr 17. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meeting records, 1985 May 17-18. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meeting records, 1985 Sept 13-14. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Meeting records, 1985 Nov 20. (Box 2, Folder 8)